

# LORNA WATSON

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 

Leeds, UK 9

07874315137

hello@lorna.dev ⊠

linkedin.com/in/lornasw93 in

lorna.dev Q

#### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic self-motivated full-stack software developer with a passion for programming and data analytics. I am creative with a keen eye for detail and confident having worked on a variety of projects in an agile environment. I obtained a MTA certification in 2016. When I'm not working, I enjoy spending my time expanding my knowledge and skills on a variety of side projects and personal portfolio website. I'm currently working a lot with Node.js, firebase (hosting, cloud functions), Heruko and Angular 9 in my spare time. I'm wanting to learn Docker next.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FPIPHANY**

MAR 2020 - CURRENT

#### .NET Developer

Epiphany is a search marketing agency owned by Jaywing who are a consulting business located across the UK and Australia.

- Primarily a back-end developer working on Umbraco websites
- Bug fixes and new features for existing projects

#### SRCI

MAR 2019 - MAR 2020

#### Software Developer

- Develop a marketing website based from a brochure for an award-winning training provider offering primary care training courses to practice managers and staff in the primary care sector
- Post 2 months completion of developing another marketing site, half of the new subscriptions (not renewals) came from the integration of Salesforce API I setup
- Develop a console app to run overnight with the purpose of creating a thumbnail image version for each image to improve page speeds for My Surgery Website. The live run took 24 minutes to check through 153 practices with 18k images and create 17k thumbnails. With no errors occurred the end result was a huge 14 second improvement

#### SPCI

#### Junior Software Developer

JAN 2017 - FEB 2019

SRCL is part of Stericycle which provides healthcare services to customers worldwide mainly in pharmaceutical waste.

- Involvement in 16 projects mainly part of a team 2 being marketing websites
- Worked on My Surgery Website which is the leading GP practice website provider (more than half of the UK) for bugs and features
- Drive an Email Service Web API project that has sent 55k emails between 5 products in just over 2 years
- Develop a console app to run overnight with the purpose of extracting sensitive staff training data (thousands of files) into a set folder structure on the server in preparation for ERS Medical changeover

#### ATD SOLUTIONS

JUL 2015 - DEC 2016

#### Junior Software Developer

ATD Solutions is an IT consultancy services company specialising in the design and delivery of projects within the commercial, finance and insurance industries

- Work with the software development team to research, design, develop, test and deliver business goal supporting solutions
- Work with end-users to identify opportunities for improvement of current and future applications/solutions
- Peer code reviews

#### CALDEDVALE TECHNOLOGY

JUL 2013 - JUL 2014

### Software Developer

Caldervale Technology manufactures a range of tooling and equipment for installing plastic pipe systems. I developed a Win Forms app to replace an existing and outdated app (in VB), plus attended and participated in monthly design review meetings. I also produced a user manual and documentation

### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF **HUDDERSFIELD** 

SEPT 2011 - JUN 2015

### **BSc (Hons) Computing**

Achieved 2:2 and completed a year placement at Caldervale Technology

#### LEEDS CITY COLLEGE **TECHNOLOGY CAMPUS**

SEPT 2009 - JUN 2011

#### Software Development

9 GCSEs

Achieved DMM for National Diploma

## ALLERTON HIGH SEPT 2004 - JUL 2009

SCHOOL

Achieved 9 GCSEs C grade and above (including Maths and English)

#### **SKILLS**

C#, JavaScript, jQuery .NET Core, CSS Less, Linq, Entity Framework, REST API, CI/CD, Umbraco, MS SQL, Bootstrap, Angular 9, Typescript, Azure DevOps, Git, Swagger, Firebase (hosting, cloud functions), Node.js

#### **INTERESTS**

I like to spend my spare time working on my personal website and projects. Currently developing an epilepsy diary angular web app and hope to also create a mobile app using flutter. I enjoy horror/thriller films and dark crime TV shows. I am always trying to find any excuse to create worksheets i.e. monthly expenses; I like data analysis and also research. Love a good dad joke.

#### **AWARDS**

- GEM Award for exceeding project expectations @ SRCL Tasked with restyling a website and implementing a wizard the customer uses to create an account. Under tight deadlines and amongst working on other projects I put in a lot effort and stayed late several times to ensure the quality of the end product was at it's best. I received a GEM award for going beyond what was asked of me by a peer (software developer) in 2018.
- GEM Award for emails @ SRCL I recognised inconsistencies with emails across products and used my initiative to analyse the current emails and suggest a redesign based on a template I built from research. I created a Web API project with the purpose being to create, populate, send and audit emails. To then implement the micro-service into all products has been a gradual change. I received a GEM award for going the extra-mile and using my initiative by my manager in 2017.
- MTA 98 361 Software Development Fundamentals Certification Awarded 2016